oldfriends.co.nz 2014-04-16

# OldFriends.co.nz - Find your old friends! - School Reunions - New Zealand

Old Friends has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. This document discloses our information gathering and usage practices. For additional information about Old Friends, please review our  Terms and Conditions. 

**Use of your information**  
Information registered on the Old Friends website ( **Website** or **site** ) remains the property of Trade Me Limited ( **Trade Me** ). 

Trade Me collects personal information about you through your use of Old Friends and other Trade Me services ( **Services** ) and the Website, including your registration details and information relating to your use of the Website and the content you access. 

Trade Me may use this personal information to help us provide the Services to you, to verify your identity, to enforce or apply our terms and conditions, to protect the rights, property, or safety of Trade Me Limited, our users, or others, for internal research purposes, for promoting and marketing other Trade Me products and services to you, and for any other use that you authorise. 

Trade Me **does not** sell or rent your personal identification to third parties. 

We release account and other personal information only when we believe release is appropriate to comply with law; enforce or apply our terms and conditions; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Trade Me Limited, our users, or others. 

**Email**  
It is the policy of Old Friends to send our members email from time to time. It is also our policy to immediately remove any member from our mailing list upon the member's request. In addition, Old Friends may send a monthly newsletter to members. Newsletters will contain clear and obvious instructions for how the member can remove himself or herself from that mailing list. 

We do use email as a means of receiving feedback from our members, and we encourage you to email us with your questions or comments. 

**Emailing tools**  
Old Friends provides facilities throughout the site to refer a friend to Old Friends. You may not use any sharing function that we offer to send spam or otherwise send content that would violate our privacy policy or  Terms and Conditions. We do not permanently store, sell, or rent these email messages or the email addresses. 

**Membership registration**  
Our site's registration form requires you to provide us contact information and may also require demographic information. We may use your contact information from the registration form to send you information about our company, Trade Me Services and promotional material from some of our affiliated partners. Your contact information is also used to contact you when necessary. 

**Updating your personal information**  
Old Friends provides you with ways in which you can update your personal information, including changing your email address, password, phone number, etc. Old Friends will store previous email addresses against your profile to ensure compliance with our  Terms and Conditions \- specifically the use of one account per member. 

**Control of your password**  
You are responsible for all actions taken with your user name, email address and password. Therefore we do not recommend that you disclose your Trade Me password to any third parties. If you choose to share your user name, email address and password or your information with third parties to provide you additional services, you are responsible for all actions taken with this information and therefore you should review that third party's privacy policy. 

We work diligently to protect the security of your personal information. It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Ensure you logoff when you have finished visiting Old Friends, especially if you access Old Friends from a shared computer. 

**Cookies**  
Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored by your web browser in a file on your computer's hard drive when you use our Website. We use cookies to deliver information and fresh content specific to your interests and to improve the experience of using our site. Cookies are widely used on most major websites. 

Trade Me uses "session" cookies to temporarily store information to help you use the site. This information is used to deliver the right content to you as you use the site and avoids unnecessarily asking you to log in. Session cookies expire immediately when you close your web browser or are deleted after 30 minutes of no activity on Old Friends. 

Old Friends also uses "persistent" cookies to personalise the user experience, to help protect our members and to provide us with research information (such as how often members visit Old Friends each month). Persistent cookies allow us to track users on Trade Me and helps us identify users abusing the Old Friends service. A persistent auto-login cookie is also stored when you select the “remember me” option when logging in. The auto-login cookie is removed when you log out. 

Trade Me also participates in Google's AdWords pay-per-click advertising programme. AdWords advertisements appear on Google's search result pages and on the Google Network. Google uses cookies to measure the number of Google users that click on an advertisement and visit certain Old Friends web pages, or who complete certain actions on the Website. Google provides this data to Trade Me without identifying the users. [View Google's privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy/privacy-policy.html). 

**Advertising and third party links**  
Some Old Friends advertisers may request information directly from users, or link to sites that do so. Old Friends has no control over its advertisers' privacy policies, and encourages users to review such policies prior to submitting any personal information to them. 

Old Friends contains non-advertising links to a variety of third party sites to enhance the member experience. Old Friends has no control of either the content or privacy policies of such sites, nor should such links be considered an endorsement of these sites except where otherwise noted. 

In some cases, third party advertisers may also use cookies in certain advertisements that appear on the Website for advertising purposes. For example, Old Friends participates in Google AdSense advertising, and as part of this, Google may use cookies in order to reduce the number of times you see the same ad. 

**Other information we collect**  
We use additional information to do internal research on our users' demographics, interests, and behaviour to better understand and serve you and our community. This information may include the URL that you just came from (whether this URL is on our site or not), which URL you next go to (whether this URL is on our site or not), what browser you are using, and your IP address. 

Users who login may have their IP addresses recorded. This information can be used to track users who abuse the Old Friends system and may be provided to legal authorities in cases of suspected fraud. This information is stored securely and will not be provided to other members or non-authorised parties. 

If you choose to post messages in our message boards or other message areas, we will collect that information you provide to us. 

If you send us personal correspondence, such as emails or letters, or if other users or third parties send us correspondence about your activities or postings on the Site, we may collect such information into a file specific to you. 

**Membership removal**  
If you wish to have your registration removed from our directory for any reason, simply send us an email requesting to be removed. 

**Nielsen//Online – New Zealand internet statistics**  
Old Friends, like most large New Zealand websites, uses the Nielsen//Online counting system to collect information such as the number of visitors per day or the number of pages requested per day. To do this, Old Friends has a small piece of code on each page which counts these statistics. This enables us to see where we are in the list of New Zealand websites. 

For more information, [ view the Nielsen//Online privacy policy](http://www.nielsen-online.com/about_privacy.jsp). 

**Updates to our information practices**  
From time to time, we make changes to our information practices or alter the functionality of our Website. We always update this statement accordingly, so we encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on privacy practices at Old Friends. 

If you have any questions about our privacy policies or any other matter, please contact us.
